Guide to the Park City Mountain Resort audio-visual collection 1961-2002
Multimedia Archives, J. Willard Marriott Library, University of Utah
- America's Opening World Cup - KTVX coverage, 1997 November; VHS videocassette (Cassette 208)
  This raw news footage of the 1997 World Cup event and contains background noise and overhead announcements but is not narrated. There are images of a Chevrolet Blazer, the America's Opening sign along with the sponsors banners, various skis being tuned before the race, the crowds, and the racers warming up. It then shows the first run of the men's giant slalom race followed by footage of sponsors entering the sponsor hospitality area where they are served hot food and drinks courtesy of Park City Mountain Resort. Next is footage of the second run of the men's giant slalom race. The camera focuses on the crowds more than the racers during this run.
- Television news coverage, 1997 November 15-23; VHS videocassette (Cassette 209)
  11/15 KSL 11:30 PM "1997 America's Opening World Cup"
  11/16 KSL 5 pm
  11/17 KTVX 5:30 pm
  11/18 KTVX 5:30 am
  11/20 KSL 6 pm
  KUTV 5 pm
  KTVX 5:30 pm
  11/21 KUTV 5 pm
  KUTV 10 pm (2)
  KSTU 9 pm
  11/22 KSL 10 pm
  11/23 KSL 10 pm
- Craig Badami remembered, 1997 November 21; VHS videocassette (Cassette 210)
  This is a KUTV 5 PM news report on remembering the life of Park City's Craig Badami.
- Manitou Productions demo, 1997; VHS videocassette (Cassette 211)
  This video contains an advertisement for Manitou Productions. It shows their various capabilities working with film and computer graphics by compiling short clips of high-speed active images, morphing images, fading images, etc.
- Snow Power trailer, 1997; VHS videocassette (Cassette 212)
  This video contains a five-minute promotional video for Snow Power. "Snow Power is a skiing and snowboarding film that will keep you on the edge of your seat with unbelievable skiing and boarding, breathtaking cinematography and a great musical score.".
- Snowriders 2, 1997; VHS videocassette (Cassette 213)
  This Warren Miller Production features extreme winter activities, mainly skiing and snowboarding. The extreme skiers travel to Mt. Cook in New Zealand, Blackcomb in Whistler B.C, the Republic of Kosickston on the boarder of China, Killington, Breckenridge Colorado, Alieska and Mt. McKinley in Alaska, Lake Tahoe, Snowbird in Utah, Vancouver B.C, Blue River B.C, and Vail Colorado.
- Television news coverage, 1996 October 06-1997 March 22; VHS videocassette (Cassette 214)
  10/06/96 KSL 5 pm "Silver Load lift towers"
  10/24 KUTV 6 pm "Weather (quick mention of Park City Mountain Resort)"
  KTVX 10 pm "Ski Resort opening dates"
  KSTU 9 pm "Weather (quick mention of Park City Mountain Resort)"
  10/25 KUTV Noon "Park City opens this weekend"
  KSTU 7 am "Weather (quick mention of Park City Mountain Resort)"
  KSTU Noon "Snow stories"
  10/26 KSL 6 pm, 10pm "Park City Mountain Resort opens (2)"
  KUTV 5 pm, 10 pm "Park City Mountain Resort opens"
  KUTV 10 pm "Park City Mountain Resort opens"
  KTVX 5:30 pm, 10 pm "Weather (video of Park City Mountain Resort)"
  KSTU 9 pm "Park City Mountain Resort opens"
  11/11 KTVX 5:30 pm "Park City Mountain Resort opens"
  11/16 KSL 4 pm "Advances in ski technology"
  11/20 KUTV 12, 6 pm "Snowboarding in powder / Bill Bordy"
  KTVX 5:30 pm "World Cup circuit races"
  KTVX 5:30 pm "Weather live in Park City"
  KBYU 4:40 pm "Weather / World Cup races"
  11/22 KSL 12 pm "World Cup races"
  KSL 6 pm "Chefs prepare for thousands in Park City"
  KUTV 12 pm "Rain ruined racing at Park City Mountain Resort"
  KUTV 6 pm "Rain ruined racing at Park City Mountain Resort"
  KTVX 5:30 pm "Rain ruined racing at Park City Mountain Resort"
  11/23 KSL 4 pm "Modern snowmaking"
  KSL 4 pm "Next Week: World Cup Wrap Up"
  KSL 10 pm "World Cup racing returned"
  KUTV 10 pm "World Cup racing returned"
  KTVX 10 pm "Utah puts on best face for
  Journalists"
  KSTU 9 pm "Park City Mountain Resort hosts World Cup Ski Tour"
  11/24 KUTV 5 pm "Weather / Par City skiers"
  KUTV 10 pm "Weather / Par City skiers"
  KTVX 5:30 pm "World Cup competition / Olympic training run"
  11/27 KSTU 12 pm "Snow comes for holiday skiers"
  11/30 KSL 4 pm "Snowboarding class / Bill Bordy"
  KSL 4 pm "World Cup wrap up"
  12/05 KSL 12 pm "Reba McIntyre ski injury"
  12/05 KSTU 12 pm "Reba McIntyre ski injury"
  12/20 KSTU 7 am "Santa visits Park City Ski Resort"
  12/21 KTVX 5:30 pm "Ski resorts expect record year"
  KTVX 10 pm "Ski resorts expect record year"
  12/22 KSL 5:30 pm "Fresh powder at Ski Areas"
  KSL 10 pm "Fresh powder at Ski Areas"
  12/25 KTVX 10 pm "Mega-mergers in ski industry"
  12/28 KSL 4 pm "Steep Thrills: Park City Mountain Resort's Jupiter Bowl"
  1/4/97 KUTV 5 pm "Huntsman Cup"
  KUTV 10 pm "Huntsman Cup"
  1/11 KSL 8 am "Fitkids: Cancer survivors learn to ski"
  KSL 4 pm "Parabolic skis"
  1/29 KTVX 10 pm "Ski for the environment tomorrow"
  1/30 KTVX 5:30 pm "Women only ski lessons"
  2/19 KSTU 9 pm "Park City ski area changes name"
  2/22 KSL 5pm "Special needs skier programs"
  KTVX 10 pm "This week on Utah 1997: Skiing in Utah"
  2/23 KSL 5pm "Ski industry shows"
  KTVX 5 pm "Parabolic skis"
  KTVX 5:30 pm "specialized programs at ski resorts"
  KTVX 10 pm "Specialized ski programs"
  2/24 KUTV 6 pm "Season health center at Park City Mountain Resort"
  3/11 KSL 5 pm "70 Plus skier club"
  KSL 6:30 pm "70 Plus skier club"
  KTVX 10 pm "70 Plus skier club"
  KSTU 9 pm "70 Plus skier club"
  3/12 KSTU 12 pm "70 Plus skier club"
  3/15 KSL 5 pm "History of Park City Mountain Resort"
  KTVX 5:30 pm "Ability ski challenge"
  3/22 KSL 5 pm "Ski slate/70 plus ski club"
- Ski Utah, 1998 February 27; VHS videocassette (Cassette 215)
  In this episode of Ski Utah, Park City Mountain Resort's quick carve guru Jon DeBoer talks about carving turns on a snowboard and promotes Park City Mountain Resort's quick carve classes. Also in this series, Heidi Voelker talks about her experience of competing in the Winter Olympics.
- Travel Travel episode 147: Park City, Utah, 1998 October 27; VHS videocassette (Cassette 216)
  This is a promotional travel video for Park City, Utah. It includes Park City's history, its present day rustic charm and the current statistics for Park City Mountain Resort such as the number of trails, the highest elevation, yearly snowfall, ticket prices and the quality of the terrain. There is also a review of accommodations and dining in Park City as well as a brief introduction to all of the other recreational activities for those who enjoy a variation to alpine skiing. 28:30.
- Global News and Entertainment, 1998 October; VHS videocassette (Cassette 217)
  This is a promotional video for Global News and Entertainment who specialize in sponsored news and image campaigns, public service announcements, video and audio news releases, electronic media kits, executive media training, corporate videos, original programming, documentaries and film.
- Southwest Airlines washing machine, 1998 December 22; VHS videocassette (Cassette 218)
  This video contains an advertisement for a special fare offered by Southwest Airlines on a vacation package. The special is that kids fly and ski free when flying on Southwest Airlines and skiing at Brighton, Alta, Snowbird or Solitude.
- Inside Guide to Park City, 1998 Winter; CD-ROM (Disc 219)
  For IBM compatibles running Windows '95. System requirements: Microsoft Windows '95 OS, 16 mega bite RAM, 4x CD-ROM drive or better, 16 bit color display, 32 bit QuickTime for Windows (included on CD) and 16 bit audio. Instillation instructions are included.
  This disc "contains comprehensive listings on all that Park City has to offer including recreation and leisure, lodging, dinning and nightlife, shopping, visitor information, calendar of events, real estate, 2002 Olympics, community and education, and services."
- Higher Ground: Utah's Winter Olympics, 1998; VHS videocassette (Cassette 220)
  This is a seventeen-minute movie promoting Utah as a host city for the Winter Olympic Games. They point out the convenience and accessibility of each venue, the cleanliness and safety in the city, the plentiful accommodations, restaurants, and cultural events, and Park City's proven competence to host a world-class event. They also outline the anticipated venue locations.
- Picabo Street, Park City Mountain Resort media tour, 1999 January 04; VHS videocassette (Cassette 221)
  This video contains a television interview with two time Olympian Picabo Street. Street discusses her serious injuries accrued while skiing in the World Championships in Switzerland and how they have forced her to make a decision of whether to start training in the spring for the 2002 Winter Olympics with a metal plate in her leg or to take the metal plate out, rehabilitate for a year, and miss the 2002 Winter Olympics in her home town.
- Piabo Street - KTVX, 1999 January 21; VHS videocassette (Cassette 222)
  This video contains an interview with two time Olympian Picabo Street. Street discuses the process of her injury rehabilitation and recovery and how it has effected her psychologically, her racing plans for 2002, which event she will specialize in, and what effects the upheaval with the Salt Lake Olympic Committee is having on the athletes.
- The Dream Comes True in 2002, circa 1999-2002; VHS videocassette (Cassette 223)
  This video is a celebration of the 2002 Winter Olympics. It starts out with the International Olympic Committee announcing that the 2002 Winter Olympics will be hosted by Salt Lake City Utah. It then shows crowds of people celebrating in various locations. This is followed by an explanation of Salt Lake City's three basic objectives. Their first objective is commitment to the athletes, the second is commitment to the Olympic values, and the third is providing a unique Olympic experience.
- Victoire a Ski Sur "L'eiger", undated; 16mm film Color, optical soundtrack (Reel 224)
  This is a French ski film that features cross-country skiing, helicopter skiing and a backcountry skiing expedition.
- Ski Film - Salt Lake Attys, undated; 16mm film Color, sound (Reel 225)
  This film contains raw footage of a race where the competitors are skiing on 2.5 foot skis.
- Barrymore's original miscellaneous footage of Park City, undated; 16mm film Color, silent (Reel 226)
  This film contains raw footage of downtown Park City and of skiing. The downtown footage includes images of the Poison Creek Restaurant, the mountains, and dancing and drinking at Solid Mulboons. The skiing footage includes images of a few skiers skiing a mogul field.
- Park City ski, undated; VHS videocassette (Cassette 227)
  This video contains a news report from WKYT Lexington, Ky. on Park City. The report includes the average snowfall at the ski area, the convenience of the location, and it's vast terrain. It also includes an interview with Charlie Lansche and various vacationing skiers.
- R and R Advertising - Park City television advertisement, undated; VHS videocassette, U-matic videocassette (Cassette 228)
  This video contains a thirty-second advertisement for Park City Ski Area. It features clips from America's Opening World Cup and of various people skiing and snowboarding.
- undated, VHS videocassette (Cassette 229)
  In this episode Barry Johnson, the host of the show, reviews dining and entertainment in Park City, gives tips on skiing moguls, reviews new equipment technology, and conducts a few interviews. His interviewees include Randy Reynolds, a cinematographer for ski and snowboarding films and Bob Oniel who was the director of marketing for the Deer Valley Ski Resort. This series also includes footage from the Sprint Bumps and Jumps freestyle competition held at the Winter Sports Park in Park City.
- The Park City Guide with Barry Johnson, undated; VHS videocassette (Cassette 230)
  This video contains a television series called The Park City Guide. This episode contains information on the Park City area contained in local shop and resort advertisements.
- Park City Mountain Resort B roll footage, undated; VHS videocassette (Cassette 231)
  This video contains footage of powder skiing and snowboarding, mogul skiing, snowboard jumping, the women's World Cup giant slalom event, the men's World Cup slalom event, and of the flag parade. 11 minutes.
- Robin Leach's Travel Secrets promotion, undated; VHS videocassette (Cassette 232)
  This is a promotional video for a new television series called Travel Secrets. The promotion is directed toward any company who desires marketing their product on the new show.
- Rob Bruce stock footage, undated; VHS videocassette (Cassette 233)
  Rob Bruce was the president of TCS West 16/35 mm Motion Picture Camera Rental. This video is for viewing only. It contains footage of powder skiing through trees, extreme skiing down chutes, cliff jumping, and backcountry powder skiing.
- Rob Bruce snow footage, undated; VHS videocassette (Cassette 234)
  Rob Bruce was the president of TCS West 16/35 mm Motion Picture Camera Rental. This video contains raw footage of various people skiing in the trees and powder skiing.
- TV 45, undated; VHS videocassette (Cassette 235)
  This video contains advertisements for the new programs that will be aired on a new Park City television station, channel 45.
- Promotion tape, undated; VHS videocassette (Cassette 236)
  This video contains thirty-second advertisements for a "watch and win" ski contest and for a free weather survival guide.
- Two of the Few in Jupiter, undated; VHS videocassette (Cassette 237)
  This video is a First Chute production and contains footage of extreme skiing in Park City Ski Area's Jupiter Bowl.
- Resort Cam - sports cam hand-free Video, undated; VHS videocassette (Cassette 238)
  This is a promotional video for the Resort Cam's hands-free video and the easy video toaster, which is used for editing film.
- "Operation Snowblast" - television, radio, and print advertising, undated; VHS videocassette (Cassette 239)
  This video contains a television, a radio, and a print advertisement for a skiing and snowboarding sweepstakes.
- Travel Travel episode 102: Ski Vail Colorado, undated; VHS videocassette (Cassette 240)
  This is a promotional video for Vail Colorado. It features facts about the Vail resort, dining, lodging and how to occupy your time off of the slopes. It also highlights Vail's sister resort, Beaver Creek. 28:30.
- America's Opening World Cup advertisement, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 241)
  This is a radio advertisement for the America's Opening World Cup event held at Park City Ski Area over Thanksgiving weekend. The add highlights dates, special events such as live music and dancing, the event schedule and ticket information.
- Park City giant slalom world satellite feed reel 1, undated; U-matic videocassette (Cassette 242)
  This video contains footage of the America's Opening World Cup women's giant slalom event. It begins with a view of Park City from the racecourse then the course conditions and start list are superimposed onto this image. Next is the actual race footage followed by the results list.
- S.K.I. Ltd., undated; VHS videocassette (Cassette 243)
  This is a promotional video for S.K.I. Limited, a ski corporation.
- Family Skiing, undated; VHS videocassette (Cassette 244)
  This is a promotional video for Park City Ski Area based on it being a family ski area.
- News report - Ed Poquette, 1991 March 25; VHS videocassette (Cassette 245)
  This video contains a news report on a man names Ed Poquette who was charged with trespassing by Park City Ski Area. The claim was that he was teaching ski lessons at the resort but was not a resort employee and therefore was trespassing. See item 118 for more information on this story.
- Jonathan Olch, undated; VHS videocassette (Cassette 246)
  This is a promotional video for a man named Jonathan Olch. It highlights his history and accomplishments as a racecar driver, a professional ski racer, and a fly fisher.
- Park City "800 Park" proof, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 247)
  This tape contains one thirty-second advertisement for Park City as a ski vacation destination.
- "Top of the Mountain" promo, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 248)
  This tape contains an advertisement for a listen and win program on the radio station FM 100. The prize is a holidy weekend give away of all day tickets to Park City Ski Area.
- Multi Market Media Park City, Utah demo tape, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 249)
  This is a promotional tape for Park City, Utah and contains six advertisements:
  1) Say yes to Park City
  2) Set your sights on Park City
  3) You're the reason
  4) Star lit nights
  5) Ski heaven
  6) Ski dream
- Destination: Park City, circa 1980s; U-matic videocassette (Cassette 250)
  This film by Destination Productions contains the native history of Park City, the mining history of Park City, and the current day entertainment in Park City.
- Underwriting credits for KUED program fund - Park City Ski Area, undated; VHS videocassette (Cassette 251)
  This is a twenty-nine second commercial for Park City Ski Area aired on KUED in return for their program funding from Park City Ski Area.
- "The Heat is On: Winter Heat", undated; VHS videocassette (Cassette 252)
  This video contains an advertisement for boot heaters made by Winter Heat. 2:58.
- This Is The Place: Salt Lake summer version, undated; VHS videocassette (Cassette 253)
  This is a promotional video for the Salt Lake Convention and Visitors Bureau. It promotes Salt Lake City as a great place to have a business meeting and to have fun. It highlights Salt Lake restaurants and clubs, summer activities, shopping facilities, business facilities and hotels and other accommodations.
- Localmotion: Park City ski movie, undated; VHS videocassette (Cassette 254)
  This is a television production that shows various locals skiing different runs at Park City Ski Area.
- Park City roll 6A, undated; VHS videocassette (Cassette 255)
  This video contains footage of the America's Opening men's giant slalom event. For the first several racers, the camera is stationary at one of the first gates and the racers are in slow motion. Then the camera is positioned at the staring gate. It also includes footage of the winners on the podium receiving their awards.
- SKI USA, undated; VHS videocassette (Cassette 256)
  This video contains an international travel promotion for skiing in the United Sates. It features ski areas on the East Coast and the West Coast highlighting resort facts, accommodations, dinning and entertainment. The video is concluded with a list of SKI USA resorts.
- Eastern Professional River Outfitters Utah ski vacation program, undated; VHS videocassette (Cassette 257)
  This video promotes a program run by the Eastern Professional River Outfitters where the river guides take clients to Utah to ski or they design the trip for their clients.
- Heuga / Mazda Express at Park City b-roll, undated; Betacam videocassette, VHS videocassette (Cassette 258)
  This video contains raw footage of the Jimmie Heuga Mazda Express ski race held at Park City Ski Area. The footage includes the racers registering, interviews with some of the racers on why they compete in the race, and an explanation of what the Jimmie Heuga Mazda Ski Express is and how it came about.
- Utah Winter Games, undated; VHS videocassette (Cassette 259)
  This is a promotional video for the Utah Winter Games. It includes facts about the Winter Games, where the venues will be, and which events are included in the games. The Utah Winter Games is run by a non-profit organization and its purpose is to support athletes and to showcase Utah.
- Park City racing, undated; VHS videocassette (Cassette 260)
  This video contains footage from the America's Opening slalom and giant slalom events, the street dance and fireworks show, and pictures of Park City's silver mining era. The entire video is set to music and there is no narration.
- C-Race / Fun Race, undated; Hi-8 videocassette (Cassette 261)
- The Resort Center - Park City, undated; VHS videocassette (Cassette 262)
  This is a promotional video for the Resort Center at the base of Park City Ski Area. It features the Resort Center's accommodations, shops, the convenience of its layout, and the ski area. It also highlights the summer activities at the Resort Center.
- Craig Badami: a tribute, circa 1989; VHS videocassette (Cassette 263)
  This video contains a tribute to Crag Badami, Park City Ski Area's former Vice President. The tribute reveals Craig's history through his friends and families memories of him. The tribute also includes footage from the America's Opening World Cup events 1986-1989.
- In Utah all that Glitters is not Gold: Kens Television, San Antonio, Texas, circa 1986; VHS videocassette (Cassette 264)
  This video contains a news report on Utah and, more specifically, Utah's ski areas. The report covers Salt Lake City's history, Utah's plans for hosting the 1998 Winter Olympics, the history of Park City, the Park City Ski Resort's facilities, Deer Valley's facilities, the Homestead's facilities, and Park West's facilities.
- Peek 'n Peak incorporation to WICU Television, undated; VHS videocassette (Cassette 265)
  This video contains a news report on Holly Flanders. The report includes Flanders' skiing history and her tips for young Peek 'n Peak ski team members.
- Peek 'n Peak news report, undated; VHS videocassette (Cassette 266)
  This video contains both raw and edited footage of a news report on the winter recreation compared to the summer recreation at the Peek 'n Peak resort. The footage includes a race crew setting up a course, an interview with Holly Flanders, and Holly Flanders skiing the course that was set up.
- Women's ski challenge - camp 2, undated; VHS videocassette (Cassette 267)
  This video contains the raw footage of a women's ski clinic at Park City. The instructor skis down the hill then each woman skis down one at a time. The camera films each woman from three different vantage points; the first is from below, looking up the hill, the second is directly from the side as the woman passes the camera, and the third is from above, looking down the hill.
- ESPN: Toyota Ski World with Bob Beattie, circa 2000; VHS videocassette (Cassette 268)
  This episode of Ski World features a special on Alberto Tomba, the Winter Olympic Sports Park, scenes from Mt. Cook, Summit Of Extremes, and interviews with Kristen Ulmer, Jeremy Nobis and Shannon Nobis.
- Ski Utah with Kenneth Cowan - WHCU 870 AM / WYXL 97 FM, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 269)
  Side A of this tape contains a radio talk show aired on WHCU 870 Am and WYXL 97 Fm. The topic of this show is ski vacations in Utah and Kenneth Cowan is the guest. Kenneth discusses traveling to Salt Lake City with Park City being his ultimate destination. He discusses Park City's atmosphere, it's history, accommodations in and around Park City, and the ski area's facilities.
  Side B of this tape contains a news report on the possible instillation of a water plant at the mouth of Millcreek Canyon and the Wall Street Journal report.
- Park City pass rates promotion, 1961; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 270)
  This tape contains an advertisement for Park City's season passes and their resident coupon book.
- New York Stock Exchange ski competition, undated; VHS videocassette (Cassette 271)
  This video contains a news report on a ski race held at Val Di Ser in France and on the New York Stock Exchange team who competed in this race. The footage includes the giant slalom race, the celebration held after the race, and a torch light run. After this report, there is footage from the Park City America's Opening Pro Cup Race set to music, a Pro Cup celebration party, and of live music and dancing.